You have a choice to make.
Do you want to sit down
and go back to that guy you once were?
No.
So this is what it takes.
It takes that misunderstanding of people,
and they'll never get it because they were never David Goggins.
So that is what it takes for me to do what I do.
It may take you something differently.
So for me, everything has to be in the studying.
Everything has to be into this.
Everything has to be everywhere I am has to be there.
Me, focused where I am.
we don't we're not proud of ourselves for the small accomplishments what we need
is we need this monstrosity of the thing to happen say ah I did
it nah there's a process
that you have to go through
and patience is the process
and if we don't have patience
after a week I haven't lost 30 pounds
and I'm done I'm over it
so that's what I found out with people man they're not patient enough to realize
and to enjoy the moment not live in it just enjoy it there's no
finish line in life
but enjoy that moment roger
that man i lost five let me go ten next week there's no passion
there's no motivation there's no oh my god man i this is no it's
every day of your life just doing no passion no discipline no motivation all
these words i hate people i hate
that so many people fucking use these words now because it's watered.
It's someone sitting in a room by themselves
and they figure themselves out and say, God, this is going to fucking suck.
Where's passion when you're 300 pounds?
Where's the motivation when you can't read and write?
Where is it?
So how did this happen?
I just fucking did.
I just did.
I said, maybe at the end of this journey,
there'll be something there for me.
If not, I can read.
You have to learn what do you want in your life.
We have so much influence coming at us that we are so lost.
We don't know what we want to do
because we don't spend enough time with ourselves.
You have to learn to shut off a phone,
shut off a computer, shut off a TV.
And it's okay to sit in a room by yourself in a chair
and just think about you.
Where I want to be.
Where do I see myself tomorrow, the next year, the next year from that.
And it takes a lot of self-discipline to be able to do
that nowadays because you want to be so attached to everything.
You want to be so caught up with the world.
The world's moving too fast.
The world's moving
so fast that you're trying to keep up to the point
where you lose yourself.
If I want to be great,
I'm not trying to maximize money or maximize people knowing me.
I do these things
because maybe someone out there will understand me
and get it
and say, I can grow from this guy and others just won't.
A lot of people,
most people don't want it
that badly, which is why they always ask the question,
how do you get to
where you are you know how to do it you know exactly how to be you
or how to be me you don't want to do it
so i can't make you do it you have to explore examine the insides of yourself
and what do you really want out of life your friend a lot of
people out here just don't want it
so guess what have fun with your life the reason why we go back
to old habits is
because our goals are too lofty.
We're not achieving our goals fast enough.
So what happens is, you know what?
Oh, man, we're very impatient nowadays.
For me, it was good.
I didn't have a phone.
I was out of this world by myself.
It was a race against David Goggins.
It wasn't a race against,
God, I want to look good for this person or that person.
It was me.
I got to change myself.
There's no luck in this game, man.
There may be a little bit of luck,
But the luck happens
after you bust your ass
and you put yourself in that lucky situation Luck doesn't happen.
You put yourself in that situation where luck might fucking happen.
Maybe you're you want to be nobody Maybe you're happy exactly
where you are in life
because obviously you are Maybe you don't have the determination to be somebody better than
who you are.
There's a lot of average
And it makes me
so fucking mad Every day I walk this earth
and I see average all over the fucking place
and they want to ask me.
How did you do it?
I can't tell you how could you not gonna fucking you're not gonna do it.
A Lot of people think self-talk works it does
but doesn't work without the suffering Before your mind starts saying we need self-talk.
So what I tell myself is I go back to the months in years
of preparation to get to
that day and I'm telling myself the 3 30 in the morning
and I'm looking at my shoes
and I want to go out there
and run 30 miles I have to in
that second in
that moment of this self-talk my mind said you gotta find more you gotta
find more I once again calm down go back into my mind in my
cookie jar I call it
and I have to reflect back on the shit I did to get here
and that becomes my self-talk Self-talk does not work unless it is real.
Most of us lie to ourselves in this self-talk.
It doesn't work.
It has to be real.
It has to be something that you've done.